<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DocuSign Dev Blog</title><atom:link href="http://localhost:8080/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><link>http://localhost:8080</link><description>Brought to you by the development teams at DocuSign</description><pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2013 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate><generator>Wintersmith - https://github.com/jnordberg/wintersmith</generator><language>en</language><item><title>Hackathon!</title><link>http://localhost:8080/articles/docusign-hackathon-2013/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2013 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/docusign-hackathon-2013/</guid><author></author><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:8080/articles/docusign-hackathon-2013/hackathon2013-big.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:8080/articles/docusign-hackathon-2013/hackathon2013-big.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DocuSign Hackathon 2013&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For two days last month, all the DocuSign engineering, design, and product development teams converged on San Francisco for a company hackathon. It was an opportunity to put aside sprint goals and product roadmaps for a little while, think completely out of the box, work with people we don&amp;#39;t usually work with, and build some awesome new features and prototypes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some teams built internal tools to streamline our workflows and automate previously-manual processes. Many of the proofs-of-concept were customer-facing features that will be put on the product roadmap. One team imagined ways &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.html5rocks.com/en/tutorials/getusermedia/intro/&quot;&gt;HTML5 camera support&lt;/a&gt; and real-time chat could be integrated into the product. Another project added real-time editing to our Send flow.
There was a visualization of DocuSign usage with dots all over a 3D globe, that we hope to put on a big screen in the office soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the projects was creating this dev blog. So, welcome! We hope to introduce you to our great teams, show you all the cool stuff we build, open-source some of our code, and stimulate many interesting conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item></channel></rss>